Hi, in this lesson, I want to show you the purpose of using chat mode, how you can use it and what are popular use cases.
So, the chat mode looks through your pod base and gets some information without changing anything until you how you can clear your case applies its changes.
You can use chat mode to ask questions about your code base, some technology concepts, about how the framework works.
It's useful for getting a better understanding of your code base, brainstorming some ideas and getting help with coding tasks.
Let's go through some examples, you might use in your applications. For example, you can ask questions about your code base, if you have a React application or any other, like you can ask, okay, how this component works or what this component do.
What does this function do or explain how this function works and if you don't know it's not clear to you.
You can also brainstorm ideas, this is what I use to really open. For example, I have a class, I don't know how to name a method and I just asked AI, give me five ideas, how to name this method.
And I'm just telling the purpose, for example, how to name method or, you know, check the password or store the password, it will give you some ideas so you can choose.
If you have a file, you need to write some unit test, you can ask, okay, what is cases I should cover for this component or for this function.
Or if you use with CSS and you don't know, you don't want to dive into details, how to center the model window by vertical and horizontal.
Or you can just ask, okay, how I can center this model window using CSS or title window, so it will give you some ideas.
For example, how I can improve the performance of my application, if you analyze it.
You can also provide us to provide, you know, two, three different ways, how to implement the feature and you will choose the best option you like.
For example, you can get some help with student task, if you implemented a new component, you can ask, okay, how to implement this component, which I know the least of obvious students and you explain what information you want to display and it will suggest you how to do it.
The responses might include some pod suggestions as you'll remember from previous lessons, so it will look like this block, which you can apply.
It won't apply automatically because it's chat mode, but you can apply it manually.
So let's see how it works, so I will ask some questions. For example, I want to know what is the common patterns and I can just ask, okay, what are common patterns.
Okay, I'm just asking what are common patterns and let's see. And as you see, it's totally different answers from what I expected. It's, he's saying, okay, there are some object creating mechanism, some object composition, he telling me about some patterns, how to write and organize the code in general.
And it's not what I'm asking, so it means that you need to be more clear in your questions. For example, you can ask what are common patterns from my file or like you can select the file you have right here, click on chat and it will send the lines of your code to chat.
So then you can ask what are common patterns. And now you see, okay, what is it? It's referred to predictable sequences or repeated characters that make passwords easy to guess.
Okay, you see. And for example, if you want extended, like, at five more common patterns, my array, let's see.
Okay, you see, he's generating the code and he's doing some suggestion right here. Okay, and I can click apply. When I click apply, you see the new code is right here.
And you can click accept or rejected. So I will see, as the same is a terminal, like, I don't know. For example, let's ask, oh, I and check the file.
Okay, it's analyzing.
So I'm expecting to suggest some terminal command icon run. This is the file size. Okay. He just tell me the file size and I need a
command. Command to check it by myself. For example, okay, if there was a command, just the size and bias for human readable size to tell it.
Okay, so let's say, I will have an apply button, but because of his ingested like the four commands, all that they want to use use this one.
I just want to show you an interface, how we can apply directly from a chat.
Okay, it's not really really understand what we want to do. But sometimes like, as you see from my previous from my previous conversations, we had it somewhere that it is a suggestion with a command that we can click on this icon and execute this command in terminal.
And this is what I tried to get from it, but okay, it's not always understanding we need to clarify the message, what exact we want so it doesn't mean he's stupid like it's mean look like our prompt is not clear enough to a eye.
Okay, I hope this version was clear and useful for you now, you know, more when to use the chat mode and see you in the next lesson.